<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TidyTuesday on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>http://example.org/portfolio/categories/tidytuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TidyTuesday on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/portfolio/categories/tidytuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Washington Hikes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_wa-hikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_wa-hikes/</guid>
      <description>Ratings of Washington Hikes This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. This plot shows the average rating scores of hikes in Washington State from reviews including the 10 most commonly used descriptors of trail views.
First, I used the tidytext package to extract every instance in a Washington Trails online review in which the word &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;views&amp;rdquo; were mentioned, then categorized the most common adjective describing these views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Passwords</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_passwords/</guid>
      <description>Password security strength This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I show the logistic return of strength of password as a function of character length. Code available at GitHun link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ring of Fire Volcanoes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_volcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_volcano/</guid>
      <description>Ring of Fire Volcanoes This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. This plot uses rnaturalearth to map the locations of every volcano in the Pacific Ring of Fire, then uses ggimage to plot frequency of each type of volcanoes with custom png graphics that I developed in Inkscape Vector Graphics software. Code available in GitHub link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour de France</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_tourdefrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:56:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_tourdefrance/</guid>
      <description>Tour de France winners This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I show a dashboard of statistics from ~120 years of Tour de France races. In these plots, I practiced reordering plot factors with the forcats package, and adding png icons to R plots using png and ggimage. Code available at link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Ed Diversity</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_universities/</guid>
      <description>Diversity of US universities This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I show the racial makeup of the student body population in the 50 highest and 50 lowest total-price colleges and universities. Code available on GitHub link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That&#39;s what she said</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:53:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_office/</guid>
      <description>TWSS jokes in The Office This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I used text mining from the schrute package in R to make a dashboard of occurrences of That&amp;rsquo;s what she said jokes in the US TV show, The Office. Code available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Emissions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_co2_food/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 16:58:55 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_co2_food/</guid>
      <description>CO2 Output by Diet This is a visualization I completed as part of the #tidytuesday R social project. This plot uses a polar coordinate system to display carbon emissions from elements of the diets of nearly 180 countries around the world. Code on GitHub link in the banner above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playlist Traits</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_spotify/</guid>
      <description>Spotify Playlist Traits This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I used the spotifyr package to mine data from my own custom Spotify playlists. I then used a polar web plot to visualize characteristics of sonic traits of songs in each playlist. Code available at link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Dog Shelters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_dogs/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing the supply chain of US shelter dogs. This plot is one of my first contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I developed a chord plot of shelter dog origins vs destinations, then a map of the most common shelter dog breeds per state. Code available at GitHub link in banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Song Trees</title>
      <link>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_christmassongs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/portfolio/tt_christmassongs/</guid>
      <description>Christmas Songs in the Billboard top 100 This plot is one of my contributions to the #TidyTuesday R social project. Here, I created custom christmas-tree-shaped geoms to display the number and duration of christmas songs in the billboard top 100 yearly for ~60 years. Code can be found on my GitHub - link in banner above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
