<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>just for fun on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/just-for-fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in just for fun on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:57:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/just-for-fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday Contributions</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/tidytuesday_contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:57:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/tidytuesday_contributions/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday contributions ~2020-2021 The #TidyTuesday R community social project is a weekly challenge to create data visualizations from pre-processed data and share products and code with community members (often with the hashtag #TidyTuesday). I credit this project and it&amp;rsquo;s participants for much of my early development as an R coder.
Between 2020 and 2021, I participated regularly in the community project; In doing so, I learned several new technmiques (text processing, data scraping from APIs, animating plots, creating custom geoms, to name a few), and developed better understanding for the principles of data vis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Cherry Blossom Blooms</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/30daychartchall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/30daychartchall/</guid>
      <description>Kyoto Cherry Blossom Blooms This plot is one of my contributions to the #30DayChartChallenge Twitter data visualization challenge.
The prompt on this day was global change, so I plotted the timing of cherry blossom blooms in Kyoto City, Japan for over 1000 years. Here, I used the ggforce package to turn individual points into flowers and a trend line into a tree branch.
Code available at link in sidebar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/generative_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/generative_art/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art January On the seldom chance that I come across it and have free time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by generative art that uses functions, code, and principles of data visualization to create beautiful things. I also find it a great way to practice fundamentals of coding.
Here are my very few contributions to &amp;ldquo;Genuary&amp;rdquo;, and code to replicate them.
Prompt: Increase the randomness across the Y-axis (pictured above) Here, I used groups of four points, each arranged around central coordinates across a y-axis, and added a nudge in a random direction to each of the four points, with the nudge increasing with the central y-coordinate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bellingham Map Poster</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bellingham_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bellingham_map/</guid>
      <description>Mapping Bellingham This is a just-for-fun project I completed out of nostalgia for my years in Bellingham and to make some DIY wall art for my new home in Montreal. I used publicly-available spatial data from the City of Bellingham and roughly followed this tutorial to design the layout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
