<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>all on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/all/</link>
    <description>Recent content in all on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BioDivPoweR</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/biodivpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/biodivpower/</guid>
      <description>BioDivPoweR: an R package for assessing power of biodiversity monitoring sampling schemes. Accurate monitoring of biodiversity is necessary for understanding impacts of global change on ecosystems, but sampling designs across hetrogeneous regions can limit statistical power to reliably detect change. BioDivPoweR is an R package for conducting simulation-based power analyses on biodiversity monitoring sampling schemes to provide bespoke sampling assessments and recommendations on user-provided biodiversity data.
This package integrates the simulation-based power analysis workflow developed by Tekwa et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioShiftR</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bioshiftr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bioshiftr/</guid>
      <description>BioShiftR: An R package to access, manipulate, and organize the BioShifts database. BioShifts is a global database of over 31,000 changes in species’ range positions documented in scientific literature, spanning global geographies and taxonomic groups. The database contains documentations of range changes as listed in source publications, as well as standardized calculated rates of change along latitudinal and elevational gradients, and various supplemental data for hypothesis-testing.
BioShifts is a rich resource for studying the effects of climate change on the biogeography of life on Earth, but accessing and manipulating the large and complex database can be daunting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Actions in Canada&#39;s Oceans</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/frq_climate_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/frq_climate_report/</guid>
      <description>Climate Policy Recommendations for Quebec&amp;rsquo;s Comité Consultatif sur les Changements Climatiques In 2024, I received a grant from the Fonds de recherche du Québec to conduct science to guide policy actions for adapting to climate change. My project was an assessment of projected climate change impacts to Canada&amp;rsquo;s marine resources and marine protected areas, from which I formed four generalized policy recommendations for addressing climate change in Canada&amp;rsquo;s oceans, and developed specific recommendations for every marine protected area and every harvested marine species in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Optimize Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/project_optimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/project_optimize/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing the use of eDNA for Marine Protected Area surveying in Canada Canada is investing in a large Marine Protected Area (MPA) network, spanning approximately 805,000 km, to preserve marine biodiversity and promote healthy, functional, and resilient marine ecosystems. However, current biodiversity sampling methods are inadequate to monitor biodiversity within a network of this size.
Project Optimize worked to evaluate and optimize marine monitoring survey designs in order to estimate the benefits of biodiversity certainty against the costs, resulting in key quantitative insights into monitoring biodiversity with eDNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Protected Area Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny2/</guid>
      <description>Targeting Protected Areas to Meet Conservation Goals Here, I worked with a team from the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans Marine Planning and Conservation Team to develop an interactive tool showing how implementation of proposed protected areas on Canada&amp;rsquo;s East Coast would contribute to over 150 quantitative conservation targets for the region.
I used the protected area network design and conservation priority spatial layers developed by DFO (see documentation here and here), along with the shiny, leaflet, and reactable R packages, and various javascript tricks to develop the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Volcanoes Shiny App This is a Shiny App I made for an interactive Shiny App training I co-taught for the Computational Biodiversity Science and Services (BIOS2) Program. This app was one tool in the 6-hour training. It is accompanied by available and annotated code, explaining where and how workshop participants can add an element to improve the app.
Explore the App Here, or view materials from the entire Shiny training Here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday Contributions</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/tidytuesday_contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:57:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/tidytuesday_contributions/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday contributions ~2020-2021 The #TidyTuesday R community social project is a weekly challenge to create data visualizations from pre-processed data and share products and code with community members (often with the hashtag #TidyTuesday). I credit this project and it&amp;rsquo;s participants for much of my early development as an R coder.
Between 2020 and 2021, I participated regularly in the community project; In doing so, I learned several new technmiques (text processing, data scraping from APIs, animating plots, creating custom geoms, to name a few), and developed better understanding for the principles of data vis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Cherry Blossom Blooms</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/30daychartchall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/30daychartchall/</guid>
      <description>Kyoto Cherry Blossom Blooms This plot is one of my contributions to the #30DayChartChallenge Twitter data visualization challenge.
The prompt on this day was global change, so I plotted the timing of cherry blossom blooms in Kyoto City, Japan for over 1000 years. Here, I used the ggforce package to turn individual points into flowers and a trend line into a tree branch.
Code available at link in sidebar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Fisheries Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Decapod Distribution Shiny App This interactive species distribution map was my contribution to the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans (DFO) project, Estimating the interacting effects of groundfish predation and climate change on shellfish spatial distributions, funded by the Aquatic Climate Change Adaptation Services Program (ACCASP). The project involves projecting distributions of two Canadian shellfish fisheries based on scenarios of climate and predator density.
I used the leaflet, raster, and sf packages to create distribution maps, and the shinydashboard and shinyWidgets packages to develop the user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Data Vis</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_data_vis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_data_vis/</guid>
      <description>Freelance Data Vis During the pandemic, I completed a number of data visualization contract projects to apply my skills in various fields and practice project management and client relations. Below are a few examples of how I have applied my skills outside of my normal field of ecology.
California Carbon Tax Markets I made this series of plots for a California carbon tax consultancy to show changes in market prices of fossil fuel emissions in response to specific policy initiatives around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/generative_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/generative_art/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art January On the seldom chance that I come across it and have free time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by generative art that uses functions, code, and principles of data visualization to create beautiful things. I also find it a great way to practice fundamentals of coding.
Here are my very few contributions to &amp;ldquo;Genuary&amp;rdquo;, and code to replicate them.
Prompt: Increase the randomness across the Y-axis (pictured above) Here, I used groups of four points, each arranged around central coordinates across a y-axis, and added a nudge in a random direction to each of the four points, with the nudge increasing with the central y-coordinate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PNWColors</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/pnwcolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:57:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/pnwcolors/</guid>
      <description>PNWColors My interest in natural science is connected to my long appreciation for beauty in nature, but I find that this appreciation can easily be forgotten for us ecologists who research from mostly inside of doors. To remind myself of this connection and to honor my years in the most beautiful place in the world, I developed this R color palette package based off of the natural beauty of the Pacific Northwest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bellingham Map Poster</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bellingham_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/bellingham_map/</guid>
      <description>Mapping Bellingham This is a just-for-fun project I completed out of nostalgia for my years in Bellingham and to make some DIY wall art for my new home in Montreal. I used publicly-available spatial data from the City of Bellingham and roughly followed this tutorial to design the layout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
