<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>freelance on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in freelance on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Volcanoes Shiny App This is a Shiny App I made for an interactive Shiny App training I co-taught for the Computational Biodiversity Science and Services (BIOS2) Program. This app was one tool in the 6-hour training. It is accompanied by available and annotated code, explaining where and how workshop participants can add an element to improve the app.
Explore the App Here, or view materials from the entire Shiny training Here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Fisheries Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Decapod Distribution Shiny App This interactive species distribution map was my contribution to the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans (DFO) project, Estimating the interacting effects of groundfish predation and climate change on shellfish spatial distributions, funded by the Aquatic Climate Change Adaptation Services Program (ACCASP). The project involves projecting distributions of two Canadian shellfish fisheries based on scenarios of climate and predator density.
I used the leaflet, raster, and sf packages to create distribution maps, and the shinydashboard and shinyWidgets packages to develop the user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACLU Survey Responses</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_aclu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_aclu/</guid>
      <description>Community survey responses to the ACLU of Washington This is part of a freelance project I completed using text- and sentiment analysis to summarize responses to a community survey for the ACLU of Washington. I used the tidytext package for text manipulation and sentiment analysis, and ggplot2, ggforce, ggraph, and ggwordcloud for visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crated with Love</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_cratedwithlove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_cratedwithlove/</guid>
      <description>Crated with Love Relationship Survey These are a subset of plots I created for Crated with Love food delivery service summarizing results from a survey of ~10,000 couples on relationship- and date-night-related topics. These visualizations and results were used for marketing the importance of data nights to build and maintain healthy relationships.
All plots were created in ggplot2 with some utilization of extras like ggtext and gghighlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy-Driven Markets</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/freelance_carbon/</guid>
      <description>Policy-Driven Market Fluctuations This is a series of plots I made for a California carbon tax consultancy showing market prices of fossil fuel emissions from specific policy initiatives around the world. The specific events and acronyms denoted in these graphs are somewhat esoteric and were largely chosen by the client, but I focused on using clear annotations, color, and spacing to effectively communicate the client&amp;rsquo;s ideas. All plots were completed using ggplot2 and ggforce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
