<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interactive on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/interactive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interactive on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/interactive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate Actions in Canada&#39;s Oceans</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/frq_climate_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/frq_climate_report/</guid>
      <description>Climate Policy Recommendations for Quebec&amp;rsquo;s Comité Consultatif sur les Changements Climatiques In 2024, I received a grant from the Fonds de recherche du Québec to conduct science to guide policy actions for adapting to climate change. My project was an assessment of projected climate change impacts to Canada&amp;rsquo;s marine resources and marine protected areas, from which I formed four generalized policy recommendations for addressing climate change in Canada&amp;rsquo;s oceans, and developed specific recommendations for every marine protected area and every harvested marine species in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Protected Area Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny2/</guid>
      <description>Targeting Protected Areas to Meet Conservation Goals Here, I worked with a team from the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans Marine Planning and Conservation Team to develop an interactive tool showing how implementation of proposed protected areas on Canada&amp;rsquo;s East Coast would contribute to over 150 quantitative conservation targets for the region.
I used the protected area network design and conservation priotity spatial layers developed by DFO (see documentation here and here), along with the shiny, leaflet, and reactable R packages, and various javascript tricks to develop the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Volcanoes Shiny App This is a Shiny App I made for an interactive Shiny App training I co-taught for the Computational Biodiversity Science and Services (BIOS2) Program. This app was one tool in the 6-hour training. It is accompanied by available and annotated code, explaining where and how workshop participants can add an element to improve the app.
Explore the App Here, or view materials from the entire Shiny training Here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Fisheries Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Decapod Distribution Shiny App This interactive species distribution map was my contribution to the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans (DFO) project, Estimating the interacting effects of groundfish predation and climate change on shellfish spatial distributions, funded by the Aquatic Climate Change Adaptation Services Program (ACCASP). The project involves projecting distributions of two Canadian shellfish fisheries based on scenarios of climate and predator density.
I used the leaflet, raster, and sf packages to create distribution maps, and the shinydashboard and shinyWidgets packages to develop the user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
