<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interactive on Jake Lawlor</title>
    <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/interactive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interactive on Jake Lawlor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/categories/interactive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/shiny_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Volcanoes Shiny App This is a Shiny App I made for an interactive Shiny App training I co-taught for the Computational Biodiversity Science and Services (BIOS2) Program. This app was one tool in the 6-hour training. It is accompanied by available and annotated code, explaining where and how workshop participants can add an element to improve the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Fisheries Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakelawlor.github.io/portfolio/dfo_shiny/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Decapod Distribution Shiny App This interactive species distribution map was my contribution to the Canadian Department of Fisheries and Oceans (DFO) project, Estimating the interacting effects of groundfish predation and climate change on shellfish spatial distributions, funded by the Aquatic Climate Change Adaptation Services Program (ACCASP). The project involves projecting distributions of two Canadian shellfish fisheries based on scenarios of climate and predator density.
I used the leaflet, raster, and sf packages to create distribution maps, and the shinydashboard and shinyWidgets packages to develop the user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
